<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0"
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">
<!--
 Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one or more
 contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file distributed with
 this work for additional information regarding copyright ownership.
 The ASF licenses this file to You under the Apache License, Version 2.0
 (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
 the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at

     http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

 Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
 distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
 WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
 See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
 limitations under the License.
-->
  <properties></properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Installation"></section>
    <p>The Python cloud scripts enable you to run Hadoop on cloud providers. A working cluster will
    start immediately with one command. It's ideal for running temporary Hadoop clusters to carry
    out a proof of concept, or to run a few one-time jobs. Currently, the scripts support Amazon
    EC2 only, but in the future other cloud providers may also be supported.</p>
    <p>Amazon Machine Images (AMIs) and associated launch scripts are provided that make it easy to
    run Hadoop on EC2. Note that the AMIs contain only base packages (such as Java), and not a
    particular version of Hadoop because Hadoop is installed at launch time.</p>
    <p>
      <b>In this section, command lines that start with 
      <tt>#</tt> are executed on a cloud instance, and command lines starting with a 
      <tt>%</tt> are executed on your workstation.</b>
    </p>
    <subsection name="Installing the Python Cloud Scripts"></subsection>
    <p>The following prerequisites apply to using the Python cloud scripts:</p>
    <ul>
      <li>Python 2.5</li>
      <li>boto 1.8d</li>
      <li>simplejson 2.0.9</li>
    </ul>
    <p>You can install bot and simplejson by using 
    <a class="externalLink" href="http://pypi.python.org/pypi/setuptools">easy_install</a>:</p>
    <source>
% easy_install "simplejson==2.0.9" 
% easy_install "boto==1.8d"
</source>
    <p></p>
    <p>Alternatively, you might like to use the python-boto and python-simplejson RPM and Debian
    packages.</p>
    <p>The Python Cloud scripts are packaged in the source tarball. Unpack the tarball on your
    system. The CDH Cloud scripts are in 
    <i>contrib/python/src/py</i>. For convenience, you can add this directory to your path.</p>
  </body>
</document>
